-Oh,I don't know. -What?
我不知道… 什么？
Well,as old as he is in dog years...
照狗的年纪来算…
...do you think Snoopy should still be flying this thing?
你认为史奴比 还能飞这个玩意儿吗？
Rachel?
瑞秋？
Yeah?
什么事？
Remember when you first came here and you got trained by another waitress?
记得你刚来的时候 有另外一个服务生训练你吗？
Sure! Do you need me to train somebody new?
当然，要我训练新人吗？
Good one.
问得好
Actually,Terry wants you to take the training again.
其实是泰瑞要你再受训一次
Whenever.
什么时候都可以
Do you believe that?
你相信这种事吗？
Yeah.
相信
The One Where Rachel Quits
本集播出：“另谋高就”
-=BT之家DRM小组 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 河马压缩制作 本字幕为河马根据R3DVD OCR得来
So that's two boxes of the Holiday Macaroons.
一共是两盒蛋白杏仁饼干
On behalf of the Brown Birds of America, I salute you.
我代表美国棕鸟向你致敬
Just admit it. You have no backhand.
承认吧，你不会反手击球
Excuse me,little one. I have a very solid backhand.
对不起，小鬼 我反手击球很厉害
Shielding your face and shrieking like a girl...
像个女人一样掩面大叫…
...is not a backhand.
不叫反手击球
I was shrieking...
我的叫声…
...Iike a Marine.
像海军
All right,watch me execute the three P's of championship play.
好，看我示范 冠军选手的三个P
Power...
力量…
... precision...
准头…
...and panache.
架式
You broke a little girl's leg?
你害一个小女孩的腿骨折？
I know. I feel horrible,okay?
我知道，我很难过，行吗？
It says here that a Muppet got whacked on Sesame Street last night.
报上说有个小女孩 昨晚在芝麻街遭遇重击
Where exactly were you around 10-ish?
你昨晚十点左右人在哪里？
I'm going to see her. I wanna bring her something.
我要去看她 我想带点东西给她
-What would she like? -A Hello Kitty doll?
她会喜欢什么？ 凯蒂猫娃娃？
The ability to walk?
走路的能力？
I'm gonna get back to retraining.
我得回去接受再训练了
All right. See you,guys.
好，再见，各位
Look out,kids! He's coming!
小心，小朋友，他来了
I gotta go sell Christmas trees.
我得去卖圣诞树了
Have fun. Oh,wait! No,don't!
卖得开心点 等等，不要去
I forgot. I am totally against that now.
我忘了我现在完全反对这件事
What? Me having a job?
什么？反对我有工作？
No,I am against innocent trees being cut down in their prime...
不，我反对无辜的树木 在青春正盛的时候被砍下…
...and their corpses grotesquely dressed...
尸体被装饰得怪模怪样…
...in,like,tinsel and twinkly lights.
挂上一堆金箔和闪灯…
How do you sleep at night?
你昨晚睡得好吗？
Well,I'm pretty tired from lugging the trees around.
我拖着树走来走去 累得要命
You got this all wrong. Those trees were born to be Christmas trees.
你完全搞错了 那些树生来就是要当圣诞树的
They're fulfilling their life purpose by making people happy.
为人们带来欢乐 是实现他们生存的目的
Really?
真的？
Yes!
没错！
Yes,and the trees are happy too...
对，这些树也很高兴…
...because for most of them, it's their only...
因为对大多数的树来说 这是他们…
...chance to see New York.
见识纽约的唯一机会
After you deliver the drinks, take the tray
送完饮料之后，把盘子…
Gunther,please. I have worked here for two and a half years.
甘瑟，拜托 我在这里做了两年半
I know the empty trays go over there.
我知道空盘子要放在那里
What if you put them here?
放在这里怎么样？
That's actually a good idea. They'll be closer to the mugs.
这倒是个好主意 离马克杯比较近
You should have the other waitresses do that too.
你应该要其他的服务生照办
They already do.
她们本来就是这么放的
That's why they call it the tray spot.
所以她们管这里叫盘子区
I heard them talk about that. I just thought it was a club they went to.
我听到她们说这个 我还以为是她们参加的俱乐部
-I'm sorry. -It's all right.
对不起 没关系
Sweetheart.
甜心
So this must be kind of neat for you,huh?
你一定很高兴吧？
Your dad tells me you get school off...
你爸爸说你可以不用上学
...and you don't have to sell those cookies anymore.
也不必再去卖饼干了
I kind of wanted to sell the cookies.
我很想去卖饼干
Whoever sells the most wins a trip to Space Camp...
卖最多饼干的人 可以免费参加太空营
...and gets to sit in a real shuttle.
坐上真正的太空梭
You really like all this space stuff,huh?
你很喜欢太空的东西，是吧？
My dad says if I'd spend as much time helping him clean apartments...
我爸爸说 如果我帮他清洁公寓的时间
...as I do daydreaming about outer space...
和我做太空梦的时间一样多
... he'd be able to afford a trip to the Taj Mahal.
他就可以去泰姬玛哈陵了
You'd have to clean a lot of apartments to go all the way to lndia.
要清洁很多间公寓 才有钱去印度
No. The one in Atlantic City. Dad loves the slots.
不，是大西洋城的泰姬玛哈陵 爸爸喜欢吃角子老虎
He says he'll double the college money Grandma left me.
他说可以把祖母留给我的 大学学费再增加一倍
Well,good luck to Dad.
那就祝爸爸好运吧
Say,how many more boxes would you have to sell in order to win?
要卖多少盒饼干才能获胜？
The girl who won last year sold 475.
去年的冠军卖了475盒
So far,I've sold 75.
我到目前为止卖了75盒
Four hundred,huh?
还有四百盒
Well,that sounds doable. How much are the boxes?
应该不难，一盒多少钱？
Five dollars a box.
五块钱
And what is second prize?
二奖是什么？
A 10-speed bike. But I'd rather have something my dad couldn't sell.
十段变速脚踏车，但我宁可 要爸爸不能变卖的东西
Well,that makes sense.
这也对
Could you do me one favor?
帮我一个忙好吗？
Yeah,Sarah. Anything.
好的，莎拉，你说一句就行了
Could you pull the curtains open?
你帮我把窗帘拉起来好吗？
The shuttle astronauts are gonna be on the news.
太空人会上电视新闻
We don't have a TV, so the lady across the alley...
我们没有电视，对面的小姐…
...said she'd push hers up to her window so I can watch it.
说她会把她的电视 推到窗口让我看
Yes?
什么事？
Hi. I'm selling Brown Bird cookies.
嗨，我是卖棕鸟饼干的
You're no Brown Bird. I can see you through my peephole.
你不是棕鸟队员 我可以从窥视孔看到你
Hi. I'm an honorary Brown Bird.
嗨，我是棕鸟的荣誉队员
What does that mean?
这是什么意思？
It means that I can sell cookies, but I'm not invited to sleepovers.
是说我可以卖饼干 但不能在别人家过夜
I can dial 911 at the press of a button,you know.
我可以按钮拨119报警
Now,go away!
快走
Please,please. It's for a poor little girl...
拜托…我是为了一个 贫穷的小女孩…
...who wants to go to Space Camp more than anything in the world.
她最大的心愿就是参加太空营
I'm pressing.
我要按钮了
A policeman is on his way.
警察马上就来了
Okay,okay! I'm going,I'm going.
好…我马上走
I can still see you!
我还看得到你
All right!
好啦！
-What are you doing here? -I thought a lot about what you said...
你在这里干嘛？ 我把你的话想了很久
...and I realize maybe I was a little judgmental.
我发觉也许我是有点太苛刻了
Yeah. Oh,but,oh.
对，可是…
Now,now,Phoebe,remember...
菲比，记住…
...they're just fulfilling their Christmas
它们只是在实现他们的圣诞…
-Destiny. Yes. -Sure.
宿命 没错
That one doesn't look very fulfilled.
那棵看起来好像很空虚
That's one of the old ones. He's just taking it to the back.
那是老树了 他只是把树拿到后面罢了
You keep the old ones in the back?
你们把老树放在后面？
That is so ageist.
真是年龄歧视
We're making room for the fresh ones.
这样才有地方放新鲜的树
So what happens to the old guys?
那老的怎么办？
They go into the chipper.
拿去切碎
I have a feeling that's not as happy as it sounds.
我感觉好像不怎么快乐似的
“中央咖啡厅”
These are shaped like Christmas characters.
这些是圣诞人物的形状
Santa,Rudolph and Baby Jesus.
圣诞老人 鲁道夫，和耶稣宝宝
I'll take a box of the cream-filled Jesuses.
我要一盒奶油馅的耶稣宝宝
One box? I'm trying to send a little girl to Space Camp.
一盒？这可是为了帮助 一个想参加太空营的小女孩呢
I'm putting you down for 5 boxes. What about you?
我算你五盒，你呢？
All right. Do you have any coconut-flavored deities?
好吧，你有没有 椰子口味的神？
No,but there's coconut in the Hanukkah Menorah-eos.
没有，但犹太教的 分枝蜡烛有椰子馅
I'll put you down for 8 boxes. One for each night.
我算你八盒，一晚一盒
Mon?
摩妮卡？
I'll take a box of the Mint Treasures.
我要一盒薄荷口味的
One,and that's it.
一盒就好了
I gained weight after I joined the Brown Birds.
我参加棕鸟之后就胖了
Remember? Dad bought every one of my boxes and I ate them all.
记得吗？爸爸买光了 我的饼干，我全都吃掉了
No,Mon. Dad had to buy every one of your boxes...
不，摩妮卡，爸爸不得 不买下每一盒饼干…
... because you ate them all.
是因为你把饼干吃光了
But,you know,I'm sure that's not gonna happen this time.
可是这次一定不会这样了
Why don't I put you down for 3 Mint Treasures and a couple of Rudolphs?
我给你算三盒薄荷 两盒鲁道夫吧？
No.
不要
Oh,come on,now. You know you want them.
好啦，你知道你很想吃
Don't do this.
不要这样
I'll tell you what, I'll give you the first box for free.
这样吧，第一盒算我送的
Oh,God! I gotta go!
老天，我得走了
Come on! All the cool kids are eating them.
来嘛，好孩子都吃这种饼干
And later,I'll show you why we don't just trap spiders...
待会儿新的服务生来了 我会告诉你为什么不能…
... under coffee mugs and leave them there.
把蜘蛛困在马克杯底下就算了
I'm training to be better at a job that I hate. My life officially sucks!
我痛恨这工作，还要努力改进 我的人生算是完了
Wasn't this supposed to be temporary? You wanted to do fashion stuff.
这不是暂时性的工作而已吗？ 你的目标是打入时装界
Yeah,I'm still pursuing that.
对，我还在朝目标前进
How,exactly,are you pursuing that?
你是怎么前进的？
Other than sending out resumes, like,what? Two years ago?
两年前寄寄履历表吗？
Well,I'm also sending out...
我还传达了…
...good thoughts.
好点子
If you ask me,as long as you got this job...
如果你问我 只要你还保有这份工作
...you got nothing pushing you to get another one.
就没有找新工作的动机
You need The Fear.
你需要的是恐惧
-The Fear? -He's right.
恐惧？ 他说得对
Quit this job,and you'll have motivation to go after a job you really want.
辞掉这份工作，才有动机 追求你心目中理想的工作
Why are you still at a job you hate? Why don't you quit and get The Fear?
你为何还在做你讨厌的工作？ 干嘛不辞职来产生恐惧
Because I'm too afraid.
因为我太害怕了
I don't know. I'd give anything to work for a designer or a buyer.
我不知道，我愿意不计一切 为设计师或采购人工作
I just don't want to be 30 and still work here.
我不想到了30岁 还在这里工作
Yeah,that'd be much worse than being 28 and still working here.
对，那要比28岁 还在这里工作惨多了
Remind me to review with you which pot is decaf and which is regular.
瑞秋，提醒我跟你复习 哪壶是低因咖啡，哪壶不是
Can't I just look at the handles on them?
看把手看不出来吗？
You would think.
想得美
Okay,fine. Gunther,you know what? I am a terrible waitress.
好了，甘瑟，你知道吗？ 我是个很差劲的服务生
Do you know why I'm a terrible waitress? Because I don't care.
你知道这是为什么吗？ 因为我不在乎
I don't care which pot is regular and which pot is decaf.
我不在乎哪壶是普通咖啡 哪壶是低因咖啡
I don't care where the tray spot is.
我不在乎盘子区在哪里
I just don't care. This is not what I want to do.
我就是不在乎 这不是我想做的工作
So I don't think I should do it anymore.
所以我想我不该再做下去了
-I'm giving my week's notice. -What?
我正式提出辞呈 什么？
Gunther,I quit.
甘瑟，我辞职
Does this mean we have to start paying for coffee?
这表示以后喝咖啡 要付钱了吗？
Okay,12.
好，12
Twenty-two.
Eighteen.
What?
干嘛？
I spelled out "boobies".
我拼出了“傻蛋”
Put me down for another box of the Mint Treasures,okay?
再给我一盒 薄荷口味的，好吗？
Where are the Mint Treasures?
薄荷饼干在哪里？
We're out. I sold them all.
没有了，都卖光了
What?
什么？
Monica,I'm cutting you off.
摩妮卡 我不能再让你吃下去了
Just a couple more boxes.
再两盒就好
It's no big deal,all right? I'm cool.
这也没什么，我很好
You gotta help me with a couple more boxes!
你得帮我再弄两盒
Look at yourself. You have cookie on your neck.
看看你自己 你脖子上还有饼干
Oh,God!
老天！
-So how many you sold so far? -Check this out.
你卖了几盒？ 你看
-Five hundred and seventeen boxes! -Oh,my God! How did you do that?
417盒 老天，你怎么办到的？
The other night I was leaving the museum...
前两天晚上 我离开博物馆的时候
...just as Laser Floyd was letting out of the planetarium.
天文馆正在放雷射佛洛依德
Without even trying,I sold 50 boxes!
我随随便便就卖了五十盒
That's when it occurred to me. The key to my success: The munchies.
这时我想到成功的关键就是 吸大麻后的“饥饿感”
So I started hitting the NYU dorms around midnight.
所以我开始在午夜时分 到纽约大学的宿舍去
I am selling cookies by the case.
我把饼干论箱卖
They call me "Cookie Dude"!
他们叫我“饼干佬”
Stop what you're doing. I need envelope stuffers,stamp lickers....
放下手边的事，我需要人 帮我塞信封、舔邮票…
-Who did these resumes for you? -Me. On my computer.
谁帮你写履历表的？ 我用我的电脑写的
You sure used a large font.
你还真用了够大号的黑体字
Yeah. Well,"Waitress at a Coffeehouse"...
对，“咖啡厅的服务生”…
...and "Cheer Squad Co-Captain" only took up so much room.
和啦啦队队长 占不了多少空间
Hey,that's funny!
真有趣
You're funny,Chandler! You're a funny guy!
你好有趣，钱德 你有趣极了
You know what else is funny?
知道还有哪件事也很有趣吗？
Something else I might have said?
我说错了什么吗？
I don't know. Weren't you the guy that told me to quit my job...
我不知道 不是你在我毫无后路的时候…
...when I had absolutely nothing else to do?
叫我辞职的吗？
Calm down. It's gonna be okay.
别激动，事情会顺利的
No,it's not gonna be okay. Tomorrow is my last day...
不，不会的 明天是我最后一天上班
...and I don't have a lead.
而我到现在还毫无进展
You know what? I'm just gonna call Gunther...
你知道吗？ 我要打电话给甘瑟
...and tell him I'm not quitting.
说我不辞职了
You don't want to give in to The Fear.
你不能向恐惧投降
You and your stupid Fear! I hate your Fear!
你和你愚蠢的恐惧 我痛恨你的恐惧
I would like to take you and your Fear
我要把你和你的恐惧…
Hey! I got great news!
嘿，我有好消息
Run,Joey! Run for your life!
快跑，乔伊，逃命去吧
What? Rach,listen. Have you ever heard of Fortunata Fashions?
干嘛？瑞秋，听好了 你听过福图那塔时装没有？
My dad's got a plumbing job there and he heard there's an opening.
我老爸在那里做水电工 听说那里要找人
You want him to get you an interview?
要他帮你安排面试吗？
Oh,my God,yes! I would love that! That's so sweet,Joey.
天哪，我要，太好了 你好可爱，乔伊
Not a problem.
应该的
And now,for the great news.
现在告诉你们好消息
That wasn't the great news?
刚才那个不是好消息？
Only if you think it's better than this.
除非你们觉得比这个消息更好
Snow-in-a-Can!
雪花罐！
You want me to decorate the window?
要我装饰窗户吗？
Give it kind of a Christmas looky?
看起来有圣诞的感觉
Christmas cookie?
圣诞饼干？
Okay,and this one here's a Douglas fir.
好，这是一棵道格拉斯枞树
Now,it's a little more money, but you get a nicer smell.
这个比较贵一点，但也比较香
Looks good. I'll take it.
看起来不错，我买了
Wait,wait. No,no! You don't want that one!
等等，不要 不要买那棵
No,no. You can have this cool brown one.
不，你可以买这棵棕色的树
It's almost dead.
这树都快死了
That's why you have to buy it, to fulfill its Christmas destiny.
所以非买不可 让它完成它的圣诞宿命
Otherwise,they'll throw it into the chipper. Tell him.
不然他们就会把拿去切碎 告诉他
Yeah,the trees that don't fulfill their Christmas destiny...
对，无法完成圣诞宿命的树
...are thrown in the chipper.
就要拿去切碎
I think I'm gonna look around a little bit more.
我还是再看看吧
You gotta stop doing this. I'm working on commission here!
你不能再这样搞下去了 我是赚佣金的
I'm here to pick out my Christmas tree.
我来挑一棵圣诞树
Well,look no further! This one's yours!
别看了，就买这棵
Is this the one that I threw out last year?
这是我去年丢掉的树吗？
Never mind! Everybody wants a green one!
算了，大家都想买绿树
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to get so emotional.
对不起，我也不想这么情绪化
The holidays are just hard.
过节就是让人很难受
Oh,honey. Is that because your mom died around Christmas?
亲爱的，这是因为 你母亲在圣诞节前后过世吗？
I wasn't even thinking about that.
我还没想到那件事呢
Hi there. How many did you sell?
嗨，你卖了多少？
I'm not gonna tell you. You're the bad man who broke Sarah's leg.
我不告诉你 你是害莎拉断腿的坏人
Hey,now. That was an accident,okay?
嘿，那是意外，好吗？
You're a big scrud.
你是个大斗蛋
What's a scrud?
什么叫斗蛋？
Why don't you look in the mirror,scrud?
照镜子就看到了，斗蛋
I don't have to. I can just look at you.
我不用照镜子 我看你就行了
All right,girls...
好，各位小女孩…
...and man.
和大男人
Let's see your final tallies.
我们看看大家的总成绩
Debbie.
黛比
Three hundred and twenty-one boxes of cookies. Very nice.
321盒饼干，很好
Not nice enough.
还不够好
Charla.
夏拉
Two hundred and seventy-eight.
278盒
Sorry,dear,but still good.
对不起，亲爱的 但还是不错
Good for a scrud.
对斗蛋来说是不错
Yes,Elizabeth.
你呢，伊莉莎白？
Eight hundred and seventy-one.
871盒
That's crap!
乱盖
Sister Brown Bird.
棕鸟修女
Good going.
做得好
Who's next?
下一个是谁？
-Hi there. -Hi.
嗨 嗨
And batting for Sarah...
替莎拉代打的…
... Ross Geller.
罗斯盖勒
Eight hundred and seventy-two.
872盒
Although,it looks like you bought an awful lot of cookies yourself.
不过看样子 你自己买了一大堆饼干
That is because my doctor says that I have...
那是因为我的医生说我有…
...a very serious...
很严重的…
... nougat...
果仁糖…
...deficiency.
不足…
Tell us what happened,Brown Bird Ross.
把事情的经过告诉我们 棕鸟罗斯
I lost. Some little girl loaned her uniform to her 19-year-old sister...
我输了，有个小女孩 把制服借给19岁的姐姐
...who went down to the U. S. S. Nimitz and sold over 2000 boxes.
她到美国轮船尼米兹号… 卖掉了两千多盒
-How'd the interview go? -Oh,I blew it.
面试怎么样？ 我搞砸了
I wouldn't have even hired me.
连我自己都不会请我
Come here,sweetie.
过来，甜心
Listen...
听我说…
...you're gonna go on,like, 1000 interviews before you get a job.
找到工作之前 要应徵一千次…
That's not how that was supposed to come out.
这种情形应该不会发生
This is just the worst Christmas ever.
这是最糟糕的圣诞节
Maybe you should just stay here at the coffeehouse.
也许你应该留在咖啡厅
I can't. It's too late. Terry already hired that girl over there.
不行了，太迟了 泰瑞已经请了那个女孩
Look at her.
你们看看她
She's even got waitress experience.
她还有当服务生的经验
Last night she was...
昨天晚上，她还…
...teaching everybody how to make...
教大家把…
... napkins...
餐巾…
...into....
折成…
That word was "swans."
她说的是“天鹅”
Well,seeing that drunk Santa wet himself really perked up my Christmas.
看到酒醉的圣诞老人撒尿 我的圣诞节可真快乐
Oh,my God!
我的天
Merry Christmas!
圣诞快乐
You saved them! You guys!
你们救了他们…
Oh,God,you're the best!
老天，你们太棒了
Looks like Night of the Living Dead Christmas Trees.
好像是 “生不如死的圣诞树之夜”
Yeah,this is she.
对，我就是
You're kidding! You're kidding!
你开玩笑…
Oh,thank you! I love you!
谢谢，我爱你
Sure,everybody loves a kidder.
当然啦 大家都喜欢听人家开玩笑
I got the job!
我找到工作了
That's great.
太好了
God bless us,everyone!
上帝保佑我们大家
Here we go. I'm serving my last cup of coffee.
来，这是我最后一次端咖啡
There you go.
来
Enjoy.
用心品尝吧
-Should I tell her I ordered tea? -No.
我该告诉她我点的是咖啡吗？ 不要说
Excuse me,everyone?
对不起，各位？
This is my last night working here...
这是我在这里 工作的最后一夜…
...and I just wanted to say...
我只想说…
...that I made some good friends here.
我在这里交了一些好朋友…
And it's just time to move on.
现在是向前走的时候了
And no offense to everybody who still works here...
我无意冒犯 各位留在这里的人
... but you have no idea how good it feels to say...
但你们不知道我多庆幸…
...that as of this moment...
可以在这一刻说…
... I will never have to make coffee again.
我再也不必冲咖啡了…
Now,Mr. IKaplan Sr. Iikes his coffee strong.
老卡普兰先生喜欢喝浓咖啡
So you want to use two bags instead of one.
所以一包不够，要用两包
Now,pay attention. This part's tricky.
注意听好了，这里很需要技巧
See,some people use filters just once....
有些人的滤纸只用一次
I'm sorry you didn't get to go to Space Camp...
我很遗撼你不能参加太空营
...and I'm hoping that maybe somehow this may help make up for it. Okay?
我希望这个或许 能帮我补偿你，好吗？
Presenting...
接下来是…
...Sarah Tuddle's Private Very Special Space Camp!
莎拉图多的私人特制太空营
You don't have to do this.
你不必这么做的
Oh,come on,here we go!
别客气，来吧
Stand by for mission countdown!
准备倒数
Ten.
Nine.
Eight.
Okay,blast off!
好，发射
I'm an alien! I'm an alien!
我是外星人…
Oh,no! An asteroid!
不，小行星来了